Okay, we're going to get started hello everyone
and welcome to the third and final day of build I hope you're having a great conference.
I really want to thank you to take the time to come to our session.
So, let's get started with a quick show of hands first.
Please raise your hand if today you have
an app currently published in any of apps so across platforms windows
ios android so pretty much almost everybody now keep your hands
...if you're interested in making money.
I think even more people
...hands than in the first question which is good so,
according to the latest numbers of this...in the industry.
More than has of you.
Are probably making less than one thousand dollars per month?
Very interested in making more than that.
I'm happy to say that you came to the right session.
So, my name is envelopes and I have here with me james
Were both program managers in the windows...team.
And,...super excited today to come here and talk to all of you about a number of
improvements that we're doing with windows...to how do you make more money with your apps.
So, used to be the case not very not a
very long-time ago that when you finish snap-in you publicity to the
store you could sort of relax sit down and see
...results coming in maybe move on to your next project that's not the case anymore as,
you know, when you...and...to this store this is just the beginning of a very long journey?
...now competing with hundreds of thousands of other apps
that are all competing to try to get the...attention all at the same time.
If you really want to be successful here you need to compete with all these developers, developers are all
gating very sophisticated in finding new ways to promote their apps and make money.
So, if you want to make money you need to do three things very well the first
You need to acquire users for your app so that they have a chance to run your
app for the first-time second.
You need to make sure the duos users stay engaged with
your app satisfied and more importantly keep coming back often to
your app and then third
unit to monetize by either selling something to those users.
Or by selling the...inventory they generates to advertisers who are willing to pay for it.
And, then throughout all this cycle.
You need to constantly analyze.
Fresh data.
To improve your app.
And, to optimize your marketing strategy.
So, today
we want-to talk to-you about a number of tools and services that were introducing with windows
ten to help you acquire engage and monetize users.
So, let's talk about user acquisition first.
There's many ways many different strategies that
you can use for user acquisition so, for example,
here james and I recently finished developing...latest game.
Controls all I know great name.
And, we're just thinking about our user acquisition strategy however going to
bring new users to the game so we thought about a number of things we thought about leveraging social media
within posts or new gaming twitter and facebook we're going to write a
...send an e-mail to our customer
...and get this thing promoted we also thought about reaching out to app reviews
sites.
...select number of game review sites on the web that we know are very of
high-quality and we saw we get...to review our game and publishing
...review these will drive a bunch of high-quality users are game we also thought
about running a pay that...slapped campaign to bring in more users.
And, we also had about a user referral model where we
could leverage our own users of the game to bringing even more users.
Now with all these different user acquisitions strategies.
Is very important?
To make sure that you're able to measure
and track the effectiveness of each one of these different campaigns so.
That you can then optimize and focus on those campaigns those
...strategies that are bringing in the highest quality users.
So, in order to measure the effectiveness of these campaigns.
With windows stan I'm very happy to announce that were introducing campaign attribution.
campaign attribution you can define a unique campaign identifier.
For each of your user acquisition campaigns it's very easy to use
campaign attribution you just create a deep link to your app in
this store.
...in the format that were shown in this live.
And, then you append.
...end of it
ac id parameter with the name of the campaign that you choose.
Now you have a number of depleting so you can use this freely wherever you want
your different.
Marketing vehicles as users click...this links and come to
the store and ultimately install your app.
The windows is store.
Will keep track of all of this?
By come into the new...sinner.
You'll then be able to get a detailed attribution report that you can
field thereby camping so that then you can...for each one of these.
What was a number of clicks and ultimately the number of installs...got?
But, even better your app.
Will be able to query this campaign identifier at runtime?
So, that it knows.
Which campaign led to its own install?
And, this is very interesting for different scenarios the first way in which
we're going to use these for our user referral scenario.
With can't also?
For any user who brings seeing.
Ten or more of their frames also join the game.
We're going to give them a reward.
Of one hundred gold coins of in game currency.
And, we can do that with campaign attribution with compare
attribution our game can generate on-the-fly campaign id.
And, give a...into the user then can be shared across their networks of
friends?
And, then add runtime we can checking the app and verify and track.
How many users each one of these users brought and then give them the appropriate...
The other use for these is analytics.
Your app can at runtime get the campaign identifier
...app to your analytic solution...allows you to do things they create user
...based on where the users who are required from.
And, then you can analyze user cohorts and understand how the
users that you acquired from facebook behave differently from the users
...you acquired in some other place.
And, more importantly what-you want-to do is calculate the amount of
money and revenue your making for each of these
different user groups and then focus on those campaigns.
That are giving you the highest lifetime value of
users at the lowest.
So,...why don't you show us how to use these...
Thanks...
...recovered earlier we have a...demo application publish the store.
And, now that it's out there we switched our focus to the acquisition of new users to
our application and one of the first strategies we chose
...leverage was social media so let me switch over here right great and,
using the...new campaign attribution functionality
...we were able to track the effectiveness of kitt this campaign so all set
up one on facebook here this is a page I created for our generically name can
...so company...alright a simple promotional post around...application.
Right and...called out we're going to copy and paste the
deep link to our application into the post.
...to the end of this deep link all append
campaign identifier my choosing here I'll choose facebook here for the
posts opposes out to my group and now to show you is anal
smoke and mirrors ar click on the link here as a user would when they
...posts and it'll bring them to the windows ten store for applications
is the product details page for application you can see that the campaign ideas come along
with this here and I can click on the get the app link here download the application of
...behind-the-scenes the store has collected telemetry both that I view
this page and if I...and attributes those to the campaign id facebook in this
...case that was clicked on at the end of the url now this is
expos back to you in a new report we've added this is the new universal
...center this is the channels and conversions report for
...demo application the first graph you see here is
a chart of the page use received for...them over time.
...you can see we been live for over thirty days in the store and
even more importantly the beginning of april we got a huge spike in the number
...views of our application so all filter this report by custom
campaign and specifically the twitter campaign id here.
So, it turns out that earlier and
in april actually sent a couple tweets the same as you software facebook and
we were lucky enough to have some are executives in this demo actually retreat this out
and you can see that specifically the twitter
traffic drove a lot of those new page use that occurred in the beginning of april allows you seen here
we're utilized your utilizing twitter and facebook many different strategies to acquire
new users and we need the ability to measure the effectiveness of
those campaigns against each other to understand what do we spend our money we spend our time.
So, going down further into this report we provide a conversions breakdown table here that
does just that you can see here we've had a couple campaigns
...we've been running over time and summa facebook campaign will start showing up here the views and
conversions as you can see here the twitter campaign was great and driving new traffic new people the
viewer application...a conversion rate in this in this world of
about thirty percent however the app install ad campaign
we're running at the same time here although it didn't drive as many page views
was much more successful and converting the...actually came to view the application to...
All right so we also say that we wanted to reach out to
...game review sites and get our game reviewed and.
Our game is free and we monetize three not purchases
...additional levels or
...currency that you can use for things within the game.
So, in order to lead.
if you don't really buy a game level the game cams with.
Just a limited amount of game time that you can do so really to experiencing
...of really purchase the first-level at
least so we decided to give the first-level for free
to these reviewers so they could experience the full game in detail
...writing meaningful review so to do this we turn to the new
feature of promotional codes and...to announce promotional
...in windows ten thank you.
Which will lead users?
Redeem in this store for apps or ip items.
Directly from...center.
You can
...and create a...of promotional topromotional
...for your apps...ip items.
You can create...to two-hundred-and-fifty
...per product per year.
This codes will expiring six months once you create these codes you can
download them in a...your computer and then.
Do whatever you want with them?
In our case we got those codes and we send them with some instructions to the game
reviewers.
Then they were able to use them from within the star client
...redeem for our free game level and because this was
nih decode...an app code...for an ip.
They were able to furs just easily download the
game for those that didn't have
it installed already and then automatically they were entitled to the first.
Level of the game for free they were able to experience a full game.
So, next we thought about running...not...ad...
Some also happy to announce that we're now integrating directly
...center...promote your app offering which
you can use to create app instill ad campaigns for your app.
That will display ads just like this one as
your target customers are use...apps from the store.
You can purchase.
Bathe...
Which will show your ad?
Is people use apps from other developers?
...you can also create house...
Which will show this ads?
...apps...you may have published to the store and these are free for you.
If you're interested in more detail sources session later today at all thirty
...I believe it's sessions seven-six one which will cover...more detail.
Great.
So, we've covered some of the different acquisitions strategies that are live...the new universal
...center and for contest a demo application as we've utilize some of
these strategies we needed the ability to track how many users are actually acquiring
for application or game in this case and all the ip items within.
So, in new universal dead-center we have two reports I'm going to show you here
for contest application the first is are acquisitions report so if you have
an application live in the windows store windows phone store today,
you know, the you need to go to two separate locations to be able to view the number of
download you receive your application and the new
...this report combines all that information to one place from
the windows eight windows phone...and windows ten stores.
Furthermore we've improve the latency of the data that you see here so in the first
...the last point we have here is actually data
for application today is being updated hourly that's why you see the huge spike at the end here.
All this...
Right now you...over the last thirty days but we're also very soon going to be adding a last
seventy two hours filter to this page so she can see and hourly breakdown...close to
...view of your data of the number of people acquiring your app
in ip items this is critical as you launcher after the first-time you
...launch updates your application you launch new ip items you wanna-be able to
track how quickly people are acquiring them across the markets.
Now because you're selling your application in a global market across a bunch
of different devices we've write a couple breakdown views of your acquisition
data the first one is by customer demographics
to provide you breakdown a by age and gender of the people that are acquire your application.
Further down this page...write a breakdown of your acquisition database on the markets that you're selling
your application and the os versions that has been acquired on now is
...covered for contest demo we're selling...for free and we're making our money through
...ip items paid ip items within our application so the same set of acquisition data you
see here for application are...app is also available for each of the ip items
for selling within our applications all I've gone to the ip acquisitions page here for
...demo we're actually selling seven ip items which are wonderfully generically name one
through seven here.
And, the first report here allows you to compare the performance of ip items against each other
so...very easy to do here for me is I can compare how my top
and my bottom ip item...against each other over time.
...also provides a break down by the same pivots you saw earlier
on the acquisitions report by customer demographics...market by the operating system.
demo so far chemistry so far is both the channels and conversion what report and the
to acquisition reports here which allow you to understand where people are coming from
to acquire application who they are and where they're where they're coming from the download your application?
So, far we've talked about new ways in which you can acquire users for your app and we've
shown you how you can very quickly get those resolves your acquisition reports
...center.
Now what do you have to do is make sure that those users that
are coming in our engage with your app...satisfied.
And, more importantly that they keep coming back often.
And, there's three interesting things that you should do the first one is you need to
understand how users are behaving in your app.
Are they a is spending time on the features that you the...are
the using them in the way you thought they would are they getting maybe
stuck on a level of a game and never progress into the next one?
Are...making in a purchases and
...rates you hoped?
Are there any other reese's with your app?
I'm very happy to announce that with that windows...center now will
be fully integrated with visual studio application insights.
Which is a full in app
analytics solution that you just get for free with their windows up?
Nesting you need to do is understand how
your users are reacting to your app and what's their feedback.
...and reviews are critical the new that center gives you a
lot of new ways in which you can collect and analyze the
...and review data more importantly we're not going
to let you respond to those user reviews something that we only had we had before only
...windows phone will now be extend into all the app types the lastly you need to make sure that your
app is running well...the app health.
...center gives you more ways.
To understand if you're app is having any quality issues and gives you the right data so that
you can fix those issues quickly.
All right.
So, are contested them applications been live for a couple months now and we have a
decent amount of user base that we've acquired overtime so we
realizes team that we need to leverage in app analytics to understand how
our users are engaging and behaving within our application...
with the launch of the new dead-center I'm happy to announce will be adding a new app usage page
that provides these insights for you to understand how this page is going to work
all-star in visual studio and what I opened up here is a visual studio
twenty fifteen project for contest so demo application we've seen so far?
I created this project using the windows ten development tools that are available this speak to all of
...and specifically I created it using one of the universal store app
templates each of these templates with windows ten comes with support for an
app analytics by default with inclusion of the application
insights sdk you can see it's been added as a reference to my project
...and the telemetry client for application insights has been added instantiated
for my project.
Initially built this I just...my...the project...compiled it I built my app
x and I submitted it to the store as a part of that submission process the store activated the
insights sdk and now we are application runs on any of the windows...windows phone
...windows ten devices the...automatically collects telemetry that is
exposed to through this new app usage reports so let's take a look at that for
...demo I've gone back...dev center to our app usage page here.
You can see here that I'm able to see now for...demo all the number top the number of
user sessions for application overtime this is the number of times that...users actually started
...application maybe we'll see how that's trending over time.
I'm able to see how those are started across all
the different markets that we offer for application, application happens to be more popular in
...in the uk I...also able to see how many
...times it's been started by operating system.
By device model name.
And, also very importantly by screen resolution.
Finally another piece critical piece...critical metric it offers is the number of daily
users actually contour application every day to use it and for those
users allows us to see how long that
they're actually spending within our application so everything you've seen
so far comes by default just by including the sdk within your application building
...ten app using our tools but there's another level of insight
that you can gain by instrumenting your app with custom events to show you what I mean let's go back
to visual studio...to our main page.
Here and...
common or uncommon out this line of code here for the browse item click method.
What I've done here is I've utilize the telemetry client we saw that was added to our project to track
a custom events specifically...browser item event here?
Every time this method is called...are application runs across the many different devices
this browse item event is collected by the...and set up to the cloud.
And, its expose you to the same app usage report that we saw earlier.
Just growing down one more little bit here you see that we have a table here
...provides you with a number of custom events for application over the last
thirty days you see we have very simple list of custom events we've chosen implement
for demo application here but you guys can go much deeper if you have a game you can add
a custom event for every level that you have within your application if you have
an application...a new features you can add custom
...determine whether users find those features are use them.
All the reporting you've seen this app usage report here is a summary
view the very detailed granularity data that's collected by the sdk and
it turns out that we have another view of that data that allows you
go much deeper and that's offered in the application insights reporting
portal that's available to you by the link at the top of the app usage page you can click on
it'll open up the portal here taste complements to download the open here but,
I already have it open because this is a great them.
You can see here...same data that supports...the app usage page...shown over
...seven days here you see that your number of daily users you see the number of sessions for
...number page views.
Provides
...out by countries you scroll down here by devices by session duration here.
But, you can go much deeper within this portal here we've allowed you to
dot dive into your customer events so I've selected the browse item event that we added to our
...I can see now here's both by changing the time
range filter I can sort through all the different events
that come through for those users to clicked and hit that browse item event within my code.
Great thing about this metrics explore view is that...some breakouts of
ourtelemetry by default you can see by region by app
version but you can also customize it on your own so say it...care about the break
...by application version here I instead I want to see broken down by some other metrics such
as device model so it's very easy for me to change not only how the
data is rendered but also the specific break out of the data so all of a
sudden I can see how the browse item events hit across all the devices out there and
you can see here there's a rich set of data available that's collected by the sdk and you
can build your own views and your own slices of the data and divers deep is you need to gain the own insight.
NowI won't go any deeper into the reporting
...see here today there's another session that covers is all great detail but,
lucky for you...going on right now.
But, before you all run out of our session.
You can watch it online later on channel nine the same
as our session energy to do so if you're interested in custom events your code.
So, hopping back to the dead-center in addition to
...app analytics there's also another set of tools you can use to measure the performance of your
application engagement you're getting from...community will start off with the new ratings reports.
Every time a user richer app on any of the windows stores
that events collected that solutions collect index exposed to you hear so
this report provides, you know, what is your average rating how many were humming was a number of ratings you've
...also provides a breakdown of which ratings you...for one-star for
five stars also very critically provides you with the view of how you...is trending over time?
And, since the ratings of your application tend
very by market the whole report here can be filter by market and we've also have the
breakdown table here the bottom the provides you both with the number reviews for each
your markets as well as the average rating in this particular markets.
Now hand-in-hand with ratings come reviews.
So, answer the reviews report in-depth center which provides you with the ability to sorts
and filter through the specific feedback...users submitted along with the rating of your application.
You can sort this page and filter this page by the raiding by the
actual target os by the market by some other filters...you to sift through this feedback.
Most very happy to...within this page we automatically offer translation for reviews that
were submitted in a preferred language other than your own can see here that
...I don't speak chinese.
We use...translator translate this that english so I can understand the specific feedback from this user.
Now if you have an existing app today,
you know, that very often when users submit maybe
...feedback for application a lot of times.
They specifically ask for features or even maybe the
report an issue within your application so that's why I'm very happy to announces
...you covered earlier that were bringing the response review capability that exist today
in the windows phone store to the universal dead-center for all the platforms.
So, savannah here she was responding to
our contest application and, specifically said there's a problem going on service three-four
application through this new respond to review capability for the universe that's
...I'll be able to privately respond to savannah maybe asking her to give me
some screenshot some additional information allow me to diagnose issue with
my application say she was happy enough to give that to me and I push that a...application
...then publicly respond to this review and that public responsibly available for everyone to see
in the store so people can see that I'm engage...the feedback.
Now on the same note of things going wrong we have the
app health reports and the app health report provides you with the tools
that you need to identify diagnosis and fix bugs
and issues within your code as they arise any time that there's at crash or
...or memory failure while...applications running across anyone...phone
...windows...windows ten device that information is collected by the operating system
exposed to you hear through the app health report so let's take a look at how are can
toaster demo application is doing she's doing very poorly the first report here total crashes
in events over time provides you with the ability to identify new bugs
...as the arises you push out...after the first-time and push updates
...spikes in the graph you see here.
You can filter this whole page by the version of your application and by market
...version to diagnosis where the issue is actually coming from we also have
the crashing event breakdown chart here the breaks down the number of crashes
by certain characteristics of the device that's happening on the os version that's on
there the type of the device available memory available...size.
And, the cpu speed.
So, say that you've identified and done some diagnosing of issues within your application
...the ability to final location within your code that actually causes issue in the first-place.
So, that's why we have the failure log table at the bottom here which provides
an exposes the stack traces that we've collected at the time of the crash
within your application so open up one of these rows here
for contest application and you can see here we've organized these by what we call
symbols this corresponds to groups
...corresponds to a specific class and method within your location and I can open up the
...just by clicking link here is provides a full stack trace of the failure.
And, this is all live today so I urge you if you have...existing...go take a look
goofs go try and find out if you have issues within your existing applications.
And, finally I'm very happy to announce that we taken great strides in the new
...dead-center to improve your access to your data for
your applications all the data that sits behind reports I've covered so far for-you
today the acquisition reports to channels and conversions the ratings reviews health.
All that data will be available to-you to download through the download reports page that you can access
here show you what I mean...hopping here for contested demo.
So, specifically you can download either for data for other specific application or if you
have multiple applications for all applications for your account...going to do for you today
is an instant reports which are available for download immediately all download our acquisition data for can
...so it'll be a daily level for the last thirty days.
When you click download reports and a couple seconds...be able to download text file containing all this data because it's a text
...choose to analyze it however you want but...here all just open it up and
excel to show you the type of view that you can build...specifically?
Specifically...build a pivot table.
Using this data and just, for example,
in the short amount of time we have today all build a similar view to one you saw earlier on
the acquisitions page and I'll just build a pivot table or easily and then I'll
...chart here for visualization so this is the same customer demographic
view that you saw earlier on the acquisitions page but
now because I have access to the actual raw data from application I can further build
a slice into this I can filter this by the
us and maybe for those people who acquire my app as a joke on april
fool's day ok so this is very simple contrived example for just
contested them here but all the data for all the reports we've covered is available for you and
it's rough format so you can build your own slices of the data you can
gain your own insights that you need to run your application and your business.
And, then finally hopping back to the our
...page in addition to these instant reports which you see
there they map to the same reports we provide you...the other pages the data is aggregates only
over certain date range coming very soon we adding these historical reports which allow you to
query a custom date range of data over any granularity
for example, for...demo application I be able to download the raw transaction level data
for acquisitions going back to when I initially launch...application for ours was only a couple months but for
some of you this is data that goes back many years.
And, finally I'm very happy to announce
that will be addressing one of the biggest pieces of feedback to do with analytics that we've heard from you over
time which is that all the data here both the incent
and historical reports will be available for you to download the new set of apis
we launching later this year.
So, everything I showed you so far is live today for your own application if you have one publish
...when the store...so please go and check them out right now and give us feedback thank you.
Thanks james.
Finally things for doing the api...all waiting for that.
So, far we've talked about menu new ways for you to acquire
users then we've talked about keeping those users happy and
engage and coming back to your app and that's all great but we're not done
yet are we now comes the most important part making money.
There are many different modernization models
but these are the main three that we see in the windows and windows phone stores
today about fifty five percent of the revenue comes from a nap vertices.
Most apps have be moving for the
...model to this free model just like our control so game
...monetize by selling additional content or features.
So, we see these growing overtime a very high-rate.
The nexus advertising with about thirty one percent of the revenue
and also experiencing great growth.
And, then beta apps in some cases is still makes sense to
...your app for...fix the in the store although we're not really seen much growth
there regardless of what business model where
you're using we've got improvements to help you make more money on
any of them so let's get started and let's talk about...purchases.
So, you're been successful you're bringing in
all these new users they're opening up your app.
But, they haven't purchased anything yet.
And, your ultimate goal.
Is to get those users to purchase something from you move them from
being free users to paged users?
And, that's called that's we call that a conversion.
By showing the right ip item to the
...user at the right time you can really improve your conversion rate
but sometimes users need some help or some incentive to make that
burgess.
And, that's why we're introducing a discounts.
With windows time.
With ip this counts.
You can schedule directly from...center.
A time limited discount for your in apertures items
...easy just speaking ip item...start and end date.
And,...the new price that you want that item to half
your app will then have access to this information
...query for the list of ip items to display to the user you'll be
able to see which items are currently on sale?
And, then your app can render the appropriate ui to highlight these
discounts the users and render the appropriate a strike through
and mention that this item just for today it's ninety nine...instead of the useful
for...or whatever radius this will hopefully help viewing
...that conversion rate with users.
I also wanted to say that with.
We acknowledge that we've been hearing very loud and clear from developers that-you
...to enable other modernization models...subscriptions.
And, I'm happy to announce ip subscriptions are...windows time.
With ip subscriptions.
You can sell users.
A recurrence subscription that can give them access to
a specific content or features within europe.
You will you can choose from different subscription periods and all
the transaction flows through...using the same trusted and secure payment
flow that we've been using with ip is already for a long-time.
We're working on this...later this year.
If you have feedback on it would love to hear from you.
So, next let's talk about advertising.
If you're monetize soon with adds to the your app I think you'll be happy to hear about a
number of improvements were making.
The first one is that with windows ten it's easier than ever to monetize with
Go-to visual studio drag-and-drop the new ad control from the
toolbox to your app canvas.
And,...media app.
...have to do anything else you just do that you'll stargate in advertising revenue.
If you're using this...they, you know, that there's a number of steps you have to
...you have to go to different portal create...accounts.
Get idea needs and app...back put it on your app all of that is gone now
we're with simplified drag-and-drop in get money.
Last year.
We introduced...mediation on windows phone.
And, developers have been able to very successfully use
ad mediation to lift their...field rates all
around the world virtually one hundred percent.
With ad mediation you can very easily connect
your app to multiple third-party at networks and then remotely configure how
uone those ad networks.
To be used
...what order on a bear market basis.
This allows you to optimize...rate as well as cpa m in any market.
We're very happy to announce that ad mediation is also come into windows
stan you'll be able to use it across all your apps.
And, finally we're also introducing video interstitial is
just a new add format that as you probably know carries a match higher cpa
...than regular banner ads.
This is just a summary off all the improvements today
at twelve thirty...to the advertising session where you'll get a deep
...all of these demos and all the goodness that we're doing on that on that site.
Lastly.
I wanted to talk about yet another way that you can leverage
to make even more...with your app the microsoft affiliate program.
With our affiliate program
your app can generate additional revenue by promoting
digitale or physical content that is being solved in...microsoft store.
You can earn a seven percent commission on any apps
...music tv shows.
And, movies that are...the microsoft store today.
It's very easy to participate.
You can even earn this same
seven percent commission on all the ip purchases.
Done by those users.
Within a fourteen day attribution window.
This is way more than what.
Any other affiliate program authors.
If you're interested in leveraging this...opportunity I encourage you to watch
...prove pre-recorded video number two nine
six that's available right now on channel nine you can go watch it
and get all the details sign up for the program start making some more money.
Okay, so, we've talked about many things today and I just wanted to take one-minute to
recap and summarize all the improvements that we're making for you to make more money.
We've introduced campaign attribution so you can measure the effectiveness of all your different user
acquisitions strategies.
We've introduced promotional...so that you can offer your apps
and api items for free to select set of users.
...surfacing...center promote your app so that
you can easily book bathe or free...ad campaigns.
We're integrating with visuals to the application insights to give you a
free in app analytics solution for all your windows apps.
We're extending the ability to respond to use a reviews both privately as well as
publicly.
For all your apps.
Relating you download all your reporting data
...aggregate or on a...format.
For all periods of time.
Directly from...or through...api.
We're introducing ip discounts.
To help you convert those users from creative page.
For introducing ip subscriptions.
To enable...business model for apps.
We're extending ad mediation to the whole family of windows apps.
And, introducing video interstitial.
And, we're giving one we're giving you one more way to make
money through the microsoft affiliate program.
All of these features.
...with the windows...
Some of them with demo today and are available today
in the preview dead-center that launched on wednesday?
The others will be rolled out over the next weeks and months.
Together with the rest of windows time.
And, there's a there's three things that you can go and do today and the
...center and I encourage you to do that if you have
...at least on the windows are windows phone store can to the
dead-center preview go check out all the reports
download the or reporting play with it and
please let us know?
Your thoughts on that there's a feedback
...bottom of the portal please clique both james and I are looking at that
...were reading the feedback that we get from you
go bouquet bade obvious slap campaign started getting...users for your app you can do
that today and start leveraging vessels to the application insights.
Instrument your app create...me then...all the right places
in your app you want to do that now so you start learning more about your users.
Finally these are the sessions that I recommended
throughout throughout my talk seven-six one to the at twelve thirty.
Really go there if you want to make more money with advertising.
Six-two for is this session that is probably of wrapping
app right now go check out the recording if you want to learn more about
...application insights portal to get more insights and your app and then
the microsoft affiliate pre-recorded video...nine six.
And, please evaluate our session so that we can make...
better conference in the future with that I think...done
we can take a number of questions here right now
james and I will also be at the windows insider...for the next hour so,
you can ask questions here you can...over there for any follow-up questions that you may
have we have to...right there.
Available for anybody right now.
Thank you for all the improvements you made.
I really like the ability to respond to usersespecially reviews.
I was just wondering if there's a case in which you can flagged
of review if there are currently you can flag review
for having profanity I believe or for being spam but if
they are making false claims or putting misinformation interviews there's no way to
flagging and there's some instances where we might not be able to
reach them or you can through email.
Or they're just being troll essentially is...way to flagged them if they're saying at feet
...giving features you do give order just being...
We're not introducing any new way to that in particular
and we know that that's just something that happens not only with
aspirational...stores and
it's a problem whenever you lead users give...and feedback we're always
going to get someone who gives you the wrong feedback for whatever reason but,
at least with respond to reviews you
can contact that person and what we're doing is we're
letting that person then come back and update...review...showing
you...we show you the radiance will tell you how many of those radians have been updated
radians as a result of you contacting that you can also publicly
responsibility right and...publicly responded that feedback would be does boulder so,
that's one way but I think we're explicitly flag is not
...specifically but you have ways to address...through this in just one more question?
It's just going to be able to work with older reviews say
...updating my app throughout for a couple of years now and some of the old reviews
were very popular requesting features I've implemented now and they're still very high up because they
were so uploaded and it might be able to respond public to those.
We have some limits I don't have the details right now we
will address this.
Through...documentation so,
I can give you a concrete answer but definitely if
there assembly means that below
...from the...would you just said this is something that will consider.
Thank you.
Hi, I'm really excited about the download and install attribution and,
I saw that for our own campaigns we can just tag the...you know,
take on the url but what
about the downloads that come from being featured in a particular market in the windows store or
in a collection in the windows store is that data available somehow?
We are working on enable ingest that.
We don't have the details yet but our goal is to...you...
The attribution.
To understand where the downloads came from for campaigns you created
or...sources such as promotions within the store
or any other any other sources so I don't have a definitive
answer either but this is something we're working on and you should expect to see these at some point.
Hello, yeah, really excited about the ability to respond to
users based on the feedback on your application but I want to
as can april modes.
May new application by responding to people
who of david feedback on my previous applications allow like to no
what four-month...received...kind of information is...trudy...off oddity get
the respond okay so let me try to repeat the question
to make sure I understood I think you want to know if you can respond
to a user at the same time use that as a vehicle to promote some of your other apps
exist we have a specific guidance on how you can use the respond to review feature
and this is something that were not letting you do at this point you can always promote
a new ad the to the app that fixes and existing issue and
it's about providing meaningful information to the user at that point this is not
a it would be great but it's not a marketing vehicle for your other apps?
There's other ways which we've shown you that you can use for
that and now your second question well,...
...correct the second question is about
which formatdoes a user get to a your response
...so you can either respond privately or publicly
you respond privately it's an email that goes to the to the user?
The email that the user gets will also have a
link where they can cleats where they can click land in the review that they
wrote and modify it if they want okay so it's an e-mail if
...publicly it's obviously just a public
response that will show up both...the website for this store as well as historic client
...the device.
Thank you.
My question is if you have a
see id in the link that drives people to the store is
there a way to track those users if they've downloaded afterwards for
...purchases and things like that correct so this is the use case and we
talked about where your app can query the see id at runtime.
Save you do that and your
...and you send it to your own service or some third-party
analytic service that graphs and...id then you'll be able to use this
the track that user overtime track their purchases and understand
what revenue you're getting from them, for example, and,
I went kind of quick over that but just...dive in one level deeper.
When the way we actually track conversion basically...attributed purchase other nap purchaser that
...works is a page a page you comes in that has that id right
if any app purchase happens within twenty four hours...we consider that and
attributed purchaser conversion and then following that purchase any ip purchase that occurs
within seven days we also attribute to that campaign and he didn't...that when we walk through it but those are
the windows the standard windows we use and it's either they went through...the actual purchase
flow right there or say they...on one device and purchased it later
on say their phones that we also cover that in our back-end and,
consider those conversions either the app right...does the id stick with
the installation I mean, you know, does it stick with the machine that has the download
actually sticks with the license to users...across a different machines...would not be with
the specific machine would be with their license for your application...thank you?
...for the...one-third improvements but,
my question isnow with the reports are basically two to three to four days
...from the
...read be able to use the stage all-out in the future release
...of...time or reduce to the...yeah,
so, as a covered were the report you saw today
be updated hourly and will also be adding...of into our view the prize
and hourly breakdown so as you roll-out new versions of your app you
can filter that report by the versions of your apps you if you roll-out new version would have
a new version you would be able to see the crashes for the new versions of
your app within the...of the logic that's...you have an existing that published
today I would encourage you to go to the old portal and the new and compare
you'll see I'm more interested for future stages
...so very can be...them update the same time?
Okay, thanks everybody thank you.